Guide to the Dramatic Museum Realia,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Stage Models
  - Subseries III.2: Set Models
    - Set model for Return of Peter Grimm, Belasco Theatre, New York, 1910, B18; Ernest Gros (Location RBML Mezzanine)
      Depiction of the elaborate stage setting for which Belasco was famous. Masking and backstage effects are painstakingly recreated. The theatre had the most advanced lighting equipment of its day.
    - Set model for Garden of Allah, Century Theatre, New York, 1911, B19; Gates and Morange
      For the scene represented in the model, real desert plants were imported. The Century Theatre stood at Central park West and 62nd Street.
    - Set model for Oliver Twist, New Amsterdam Theatre; New York, 1912, B20; Gates and Morange
      Depicts a section of the Thames near London Bridge, the setting of Act IV, Scene I. The New Amsterdam Theatre was at 214 West 42nd St.
    - Set model for Prunella, Little Theatre, New York, 1913, B21; Unitt and Wickes
      Setting is a formal garden with a high wall across the back. The Little Theatre at 240 West 44th St. was one of the first off-Broadway theatres.
    - Set model for Abduction from the Seraglio (Mozart/Stephani), Metropolitan Opera; New York, 1946, B25; Donald Oenslager
    - Set model for Warrior's Husband (Thompson), Morosco Theatre, New York, 1932, B27; Woodman Thompson
    - Set model for The Island God (Menotti), Metropolitan Opera, New York, 1942, B28; Eugene Berman
    - Set model for Todo by Nogami Yaeko, Geikyo Troupe; Haiyuza Theatre, 1965, B29; Yanagisawa, Machio
    - Set model for Honcho Nijusho (Chikamatsu Hanji), Imperial Theatre, Tokyo, circa 1925, B32
      Large model of two settings for the second act of Honcho Nijusho. On the upper level is the setting for the first scene, a lakeside palace. Below it is one for the second scene, the palace garden. Shown are indications of the permanent stage house surrounding the setting.
    - Set model for Kamisori (Razor) by Kichizo Nakamura, Nippon Geigitso Gekijo; Tokyo, 1966, B33; Yasuhiro Ishi
    - Ejima Ikushima (Ejima and Ikushima) by Hakucho Masamune, 1966, B34; Yasuhiro Ishi
    - Set model for Machigai (Mistake) by Hakucho Masamune, Kase Troupe; Tokyo, 1965, B35; Yasuhiro Ishi
    - Set model for Blood Wedding by Frederico Garcia Lorca, 1965, B36; Michiya Okada